<resources>
    <string name="app_name">WildGuard</string>
    <string name="hamburger_menu_content_description">Open menu</string>
    <string name="menu_map_layers_title">Map Layers</string>
    <string name="menu_toggle_plants_food_sources">Plants, Food sources</string>
    <string name="menu_toggle_water_sources">Water Sources</string>
    <string name="menu_toggle_wild_life">Wild Life</string>
    <string name="menu_toggle_signal_nearby">Signal Nearby</string>
    <string name="menu_item_survival_guide">Survival guide</string>
    <string name="bottom_nav_left_placeholder">Survival Guide</string>
    <string name="bottom_nav_map">Map</string>
    <string name="bottom_nav_settings">Settings</string>

    <string name="survival_guide_title">Survival Guide</string>
    <string name="survival_guide_menu_hint">Choose a section:</string>
    <string name="back_button_text">Back</string>

    <string name="section_firecraft_title">Firecraft</string>
    <string name="section_firecraft_body">Collect dry tinder and kindling first, then build a stable fire lay before lighting.</string>
    <string name="section_firecraft_photo_one">Fire setup photo 1</string>
    <string name="section_firecraft_photo_two">Fire setup photo 2</string>

    <string name="section_firecraft_warmth_title">Firecraft &amp; Warmth</string>
    <string name="section_firecraft_warmth_body">Firecraft and warmth basics.</string>
    <string name="section_firecraft_warmth_photo_one">Firecraft image placeholder 1</string>
    <string name="section_firecraft_warmth_photo_two">Firecraft image placeholder 2</string>

    <string name="fire_item_teepee_title">The Teepee Fire (Quick Heat)</string>
    <string name="fire_item_teepee_image_label">Image placeholder: Twigs in a cone shape over dry tinder in the center.</string>
    <string name="fire_item_teepee_step_1">Place a handful of dry tinder (grass, bark) in the center of your cleared fire ring.</string>
    <string name="fire_item_teepee_step_2">Lean small, dry twigs over the tinder in a circular cone (teepee) shape. Leave a small gap to reach the tinder.</string>
    <string name="fire_item_teepee_step_3">Light the tinder from the bottom. As the teepee burns and collapses, add thicker logs to the pile.</string>

    <string name="fire_item_log_cabin_title">The Log Cabin Fire (Long Burn)</string>
    <string name="fire_item_log_cabin_image_label">Image placeholder: Crisscross stacked sticks around a small center teepee.</string>
    <string name="fire_item_log_cabin_step_1">Build a tiny, basic Teepee fire in the center.</string>
    <string name="fire_item_log_cabin_step_2">Place two thick branches parallel to each other on opposite sides of the teepee.</string>
    <string name="fire_item_log_cabin_step_3">Place two smaller branches across them perpendicularly. Continue stacking upward for 4 to 5 levels, then light the center teepee.</string>

    <string name="fire_item_lean_to_title">The Lean-To Fire (For Wind/Rain)</string>
    <string name="fire_item_lean_to_image_label">Image placeholder: Large log on the ground with small sticks leaning over tinder underneath.</string>
    <string name="fire_item_lean_to_step_1">Find a very thick, slightly damp log and place it horizontally, perpendicular to the direction the wind is blowing.</string>
    <string name="fire_item_lean_to_step_2">Place your dry tinder bundle right up against the bottom of this large log on the downwind side.</string>
    <string name="fire_item_lean_to_step_3">Lean smaller, dry sticks over the tinder, resting them on top of the large log. Light the tinder; the large log blocks the wind and reflects heat outward.</string>

    <string name="fire_item_ferro_rod_title">Striking a Ferro Rod</string>
    <string name="fire_item_ferro_rod_image_label">Image placeholder: Scraper at a 45-degree angle on a ferro rod with sparks falling into tinder.</string>
    <string name="fire_item_ferro_rod_step_1">Anchor the tip of the Ferro rod firmly directly into the center of your dry tinder bundle.</string>
    <string name="fire_item_ferro_rod_step_2">Place the metal scraper at a 45-degree angle at the top of the rod.</string>
    <string name="fire_item_ferro_rod_step_3">Instead of pushing the scraper down (which smashes your tinder), pull the rod firmly backward to drop a shower of 3,000-degree sparks into the tinder.</string>

    <string name="fire_item_wet_tinder_title">Finding Dry Tinder in the Wet</string>
    <string name="fire_item_wet_tinder_image_label">Image placeholder: Knife carving a feather stick with curled shavings still attached.</string>
    <string name="fire_item_wet_tinder_step_1">Never take wood from the ground. Break off dead branches that are still attached to standing trees.</string>
    <string name="fire_item_wet_tinder_step_2">Use your knife to carve away the wet, outer bark until you reach the pale, dry wood underneath.</string>
    <string name="fire_item_wet_tinder_step_3">Carefully shave the dry wood downward to create thin, curly shavings that stay attached to the stick (Feather Sticks). These will catch a spark even if the forest is soaked.</string>

    <string name="section_water_title">Water</string>
    <string name="section_water_body">Find flowing water when possible and purify it by boiling, filtering, or chemical treatment.</string>
    <string name="section_water_photo_one">Water source photo 1</string>
    <string name="section_water_photo_two">Water source photo 2</string>

    <string name="section_water_procurement_title">Water Procurement</string>
    <string name="section_water_procurement_body">Water procurement basics.</string>
    <string name="section_water_procurement_photo_one">Water procurement image placeholder 1</string>
    <string name="section_water_procurement_photo_two">Water procurement image placeholder 2</string>

    <string name="water_item_transpiration_bag_title">The Transpiration Bag</string>
    <string name="water_item_transpiration_bag_image_label">Image placeholder: Clear plastic bag tied over a leafy branch with condensed water pooling at the corner.</string>
    <string name="water_item_transpiration_bag_step_1">Find a living, broad-leaved tree or bush directly in the sunlight (avoid poisonous plants).</string>
    <string name="water_item_transpiration_bag_step_2">Place a clear plastic bag over a densely leaved branch and tie the open end tightly shut around the branch.</string>
    <string name="water_item_transpiration_bag_step_3">Weigh down the bottom corner of the bag with a small pebble so the condensed water pools in one spot. Check back in a few hours.</string>

    <string name="water_item_dew_sponge_title">The Cloth Dew Sponge</string>
    <string name="water_item_dew_sponge_image_label">Image placeholder: Cloth tied around ankles while walking through tall wet morning grass.</string>
    <string name="water_item_dew_sponge_step_1">Wake up before the sun evaporates the morning dew.</string>
    <string name="water_item_dew_sponge_step_2">Tie a clean, highly absorbent cloth (like a cotton t-shirt or bandana) around your ankles and walk through tall grass.</string>
    <string name="water_item_dew_sponge_step_3">Once the cloth is completely soaked, wring the collected water directly into your container. This water is generally safe to drink without boiling.</string>

    <string name="water_item_natural_filter_title">Natural Layer Filter</string>
    <string name="water_item_natural_filter_image_label">Image placeholder: Inverted bottle filter with layers of gravel, sand, charcoal, and cloth, dripping cleaner water.</string>
    <string name="water_item_natural_filter_step_1">Create a funnel (e.g., cut the bottom off a plastic bottle, or use bark/cloth). Poke a small hole in the bottom.</string>
    <string name="water_item_natural_filter_step_2">Pack the funnel in layers from bottom to top: Cloth/grass, crushed charcoal (from your fire), fine sand, and small gravel at the top.</string>
    <string name="water_item_natural_filter_step_3">Pour murky water slowly through the top. Crucial: This only removes dirt and toxins; it does NOT kill bacteria. You must still boil this water.</string>

    <string name="water_item_boiling_rules_title">Safe Boiling Rules</string>
    <string name="water_item_boiling_rules_image_label">Image placeholder: Metal canteen over a campfire at a full rolling boil.</string>
    <string name="water_item_boiling_rules_step_1">Filter your water first to remove floating debris and dirt (see Natural Layer Filter).</string>
    <string name="water_item_boiling_rules_step_2">Place your metal container in or suspended directly over the fire.</string>
    <string name="water_item_boiling_rules_step_3">Bring the water to a rapid, rolling boil (large bubbles breaking the surface) and keep it boiling for at least 1 full minute (or 3 minutes if you are at a high altitude). Let cool before drinking.</string>

    <string name="water_item_tracking_hidden_water_title">Tracking Hidden Water</string>
    <string name="water_item_tracking_hidden_water_image_label">Image placeholder: V-shaped deer tracks in muddy ground leading downhill into a ravine.</string>
    <string name="water_item_tracking_hidden_water_step_1">Follow the animals. Grazing animals (like deer) usually head toward water at dawn and dusk. Follow their tracks downhill.</string>
    <string name="water_item_tracking_hidden_water_step_2">Look for insects. Bees rarely fly more than 3-4 miles from their hives, and ants will often march in a straight line toward moisture.</string>
    <string name="water_item_tracking_hidden_water_step_3">Dig in dry riverbeds. Find the lowest point on the outside edge of a bend in a dry stream and dig down a foot; water will often seep into the hole.</string>

    <string name="section_shelter_title">Emergency Shelter</string>
    <string name="section_shelter_body">Emergency shelter basics.</string>
    <string name="section_shelter_photo_one">Emergency shelter image placeholder 1</string>
    <string name="section_shelter_photo_two">Emergency shelter image placeholder 2</string>

    <string name="shelter_item_safe_location_title">Choosing a Safe Location</string>
    <string name="shelter_item_safe_location_image_label">Image placeholder: Flat high ground away from widowmakers and low riverbanks.</string>
    <string name="shelter_item_safe_location_step_1">Avoid the 4 W\'s: Wind (exposed ridges), Water (dry riverbeds that can flash flood), Widowmakers (dead branches hanging above), and Wildlife (game trails or nests).</string>
    <string name="shelter_item_safe_location_step_2">Look for flat, slightly elevated ground that drains well if it rains.</string>
    <string name="shelter_item_safe_location_step_3">Clear away rocks, sharp twigs, and debris to create a smooth, flat surface before you start building.</string>

    <string name="shelter_item_ground_insulation_title">Ground Insulation (The Bed)</string>
    <string name="shelter_item_ground_insulation_image_label">Image placeholder: Person on thick pine-bough bedding above cold ground inside shelter.</string>
    <string name="shelter_item_ground_insulation_step_1">Never sleep directly on bare dirt or rock. The cold ground will conduct heat away from your body faster than the cold air.</string>
    <string name="shelter_item_ground_insulation_step_2">Gather dry materials like pine boughs, dry grass, or piles of dead leaves.</string>
    <string name="shelter_item_ground_insulation_step_3">Build a natural mattress that is at least 6 to 8 inches thick after it is compressed by your body weight.</string>

    <string name="shelter_item_lean_to_title">The Basic Lean-To</string>
    <string name="shelter_item_lean_to_image_label">Image placeholder: Ridgepole between trees with angled ribs facing a small fire.</string>
    <string name="shelter_item_lean_to_step_1">Find two trees about 6 feet apart. Lash a thick, sturdy branch (the ridgepole) horizontally between them at chest height.</string>
    <string name="shelter_item_lean_to_step_2">Lean smaller branches (ribs) closely together against the downwind side of the ridgepole at a 45-degree angle.</string>
    <string name="shelter_item_lean_to_step_3">Weave smaller twigs horizontally through the ribs, then pile on a thick layer of leaves or pine needles to block wind and rain.</string>

    <string name="shelter_item_debris_hut_title">The Debris Hut (Cold Weather)</string>
    <string name="shelter_item_debris_hut_image_label">Image placeholder: Wedge-shaped debris hut with a long ridgepole and heavy leaf insulation.</string>
    <string name="shelter_item_debris_hut_step_1">Prop one end of a strong, 8-foot pole onto a low stump or rock (about waist high). Let the other end rest on the ground.</string>
    <string name="shelter_item_debris_hut_step_2">Lean short sticks tightly along both sides of the pole to create a small A-frame. It should be just big enough for you to slide into.</string>
    <string name="shelter_item_debris_hut_step_3">Pile at least 2 to 3 feet of dry leaves, moss, or pine needles over the entire outside of the structure to act as heavy insulation.</string>

    <string name="shelter_item_a_frame_tarp_title">The A-Frame Tarp Shelter</string>
    <string name="shelter_item_a_frame_tarp_image_label">Image placeholder: Tarp draped over a ridgeline and staked tight into a triangular tent.</string>
    <string name="shelter_item_a_frame_tarp_step_1">Tie a rope or piece of paracord tightly between two trees at about waist or chest height.</string>
    <string name="shelter_item_a_frame_tarp_step_2">Drape your emergency blanket or tarp evenly over the line.</string>
    <string name="shelter_item_a_frame_tarp_step_3">Pull the four corners out tightly to form a triangle and peg them into the ground using sharpened sticks or heavy rocks.</string>

    <string name="section_first_aid_title">First Aid &amp; Hazards</string>
    <string name="section_first_aid_body">Critical first aid and field hazard response basics.</string>
    <string name="section_first_aid_photo_one">First aid and hazards image placeholder 1</string>
    <string name="section_first_aid_photo_two">First aid and hazards image placeholder 2</string>

    <string name="first_aid_item_stopping_bleeding_title">Stopping Severe Bleeding</string>
    <string name="first_aid_item_stopping_bleeding_image_label">Image placeholder: Hands applying heavy, direct pressure to a wound using a thick clean cloth.</string>
    <string name="first_aid_item_stopping_bleeding_step_1">Apply immediate, firm, and continuous direct pressure to the wound using a clean cloth or shirt.</string>
    <string name="first_aid_item_stopping_bleeding_step_2">If the bleeding is on a limb, elevate the limb above the level of the heart while maintaining pressure.</string>
    <string name="first_aid_item_stopping_bleeding_step_3">If blood is spurting (arterial bleed) and pressure fails, apply a tourniquet 2-3 inches above the wound. Twist until bleeding stops and note the exact time it was applied.</string>

    <string name="first_aid_item_makeshift_splints_title">Makeshift Splints for Sprains</string>
    <string name="first_aid_item_makeshift_splints_image_label">Image placeholder: Forearm stabilized by two straight branches tied securely with fabric strips.</string>
    <string name="first_aid_item_makeshift_splints_step_1">Do not force a dislocated joint back into place. Immobilize the injury exactly in the position you found it.</string>
    <string name="first_aid_item_makeshift_splints_step_2">Find two rigid objects (straight sticks, rolled-up foam pads, or tent poles) and place them on either side of the injured limb.</string>
    <string name="first_aid_item_makeshift_splints_step_3">Tie the rigid objects securely using strips of cloth, shoelaces, or vines. Tie the knots above and below the injured joint, never directly over it.</string>

    <string name="first_aid_item_hypothermia_title">Treating Hypothermia</string>
    <string name="first_aid_item_hypothermia_image_label">Image placeholder: Shivering person wrapped in an emergency blanket over a sleeping bag on a foam pad.</string>
    <string name="first_aid_item_hypothermia_step_1">Get the person out of the wind and rain. Immediately remove any wet clothing; wet clothes draw heat away from the body 25 times faster than air.</string>
    <string name="first_aid_item_hypothermia_step_2">Put dry clothes on the person and insulate them from the cold ground using a sleeping pad or pine boughs.</string>
    <string name="first_aid_item_hypothermia_step_3">Apply gentle heat to the core. Place warm (not boiling) water bottles wrapped in cloth on their neck, armpits, and groin. Do not rub their skin or put them too close to a blazing fire.</string>

    <string name="first_aid_item_snake_bites_title">Managing Snake Bites</string>
    <string name="first_aid_item_snake_bites_image_label">Image placeholder: Calm person with a bitten leg resting below chest level.</string>
    <string name="first_aid_item_snake_bites_step_1">Move out of striking distance immediately. Keep the victim completely still and calm to slow their heart rate and the spread of venom.</string>
    <string name="first_aid_item_snake_bites_step_2">Position the bitten area lower than the level of the heart. Remove any rings, watches, or tight clothing around the bite area, as it will swell rapidly.</string>
    <string name="first_aid_item_snake_bites_step_3">Wash the bite gently with soap and water. DO NOT cut the wound, attempt to suck the venom out, or apply a tourniquet. Seek medical evacuation immediately.</string>

    <string name="first_aid_item_burns_title">Treating Burns</string>
    <string name="first_aid_item_burns_image_label">Image placeholder: Burned hand held under a gentle stream of cool clean water.</string>
    <string name="first_aid_item_burns_step_1">Immediately run cool (not ice-cold) water over the burn for 10 to 15 minutes to stop the skin from continuing to cook.</string>
    <string name="first_aid_item_burns_step_2">Remove any jewelry or tight clothing near the burn area before swelling begins. Do not attempt to remove clothing that is stuck to the burn.</string>
    <string name="first_aid_item_burns_step_3">Cover the burn loosely with a clean, dry cloth or sterile gauze. Do not apply ointments, butter, or grease, and never pop blisters.</string>

    <string name="section_signaling_title">Signaling &amp; Rescue</string>
    <string name="section_signaling_body">Field signaling and rescue visibility basics.</string>
    <string name="section_signaling_photo_one">Signaling and rescue image placeholder 1</string>
    <string name="section_signaling_photo_two">Signaling and rescue image placeholder 2</string>

    <string name="signaling_item_rule_of_three_title">The Universal Rule of Three (SOS)</string>
    <string name="signaling_item_rule_of_three_image_label">Image placeholder: Whistle with 3 short, 3 long, 3 short sound bursts.</string>
    <string name="signaling_item_rule_of_three_step_1">In wilderness survival, any signal repeated three times in a row is the universal distress call (e.g., three whistle blasts, three gunshots, or three fires in a triangle).</string>
    <string name="signaling_item_rule_of_three_step_2">The official SOS in Morse code is 3 short, 3 long, 3 short.</string>
    <string name="signaling_item_rule_of_three_step_3">If you are using a whistle, blow three loud, distinct blasts, wait a few minutes to listen for a reply, and repeat.</string>

    <string name="signaling_item_signal_mirror_title">Using a Signal Mirror</string>
    <string name="signaling_item_signal_mirror_image_label">Image placeholder: Person aiming reflected sunlight through a finger V toward a target.</string>
    <string name="signaling_item_signal_mirror_step_1">You can use a dedicated signal mirror, a phone screen, or a metallic compass back.</string>
    <string name="signaling_item_signal_mirror_step_2">Hold your non-mirror hand out at arms length and make a V with your fingers, framing your target (like a search plane or distant road).</string>
    <string name="signaling_item_signal_mirror_step_3">Hold the mirror near your eye and bounce the sunlight off the mirror, through your fingers, and onto the target. Sweep the beam slowly back and forth.</string>

    <string name="signaling_item_ground_markers_title">Ground-to-Air Markers</string>
    <string name="signaling_item_ground_markers_image_label">Image placeholder: Large high-contrast X made from rocks and branches in an open area.</string>
    <string name="signaling_item_ground_markers_step_1">Find a large clearing that is visible from the sky. Do not build signals under a tree canopy.</string>
    <string name="signaling_item_ground_markers_step_2">Use materials that heavily contrast with the ground. Use dark rocks or logs on snow/sand, or bright clothing/toilet paper on dark grass.</string>
    <string name="signaling_item_ground_markers_step_3">Build a massive "X" (meaning "Unable to proceed/need help") or "V" (meaning "Require Assistance"). Make the letters at least 10 feet long so they can be seen by fast-moving aircraft.</string>

    <string name="signaling_item_smoky_day_fire_title">The Smoky Day Fire</string>
    <string name="signaling_item_smoky_day_fire_image_label">Image placeholder: Hot campfire with green vegetation producing thick white smoke.</string>
    <string name="signaling_item_smoky_day_fire_step_1">Build a very hot, sustainable fire using dry wood in a clear area (like a ridge or a clearing).</string>
    <string name="signaling_item_smoky_day_fire_step_2">Gather a large amount of "green" (living) vegetation, such as fresh pine boughs, damp leaves, or tall green grass.</string>
    <string name="signaling_item_smoky_day_fire_step_3">Once you hear an aircraft, throw the green vegetation onto the hot coals. It will not burn efficiently, but it will instantly produce a massive column of thick white smoke visible for miles.</string>

    <string name="signaling_item_high_ground_movement_title">High Ground &amp; Movement</string>
    <string name="signaling_item_high_ground_movement_image_label">Image placeholder: Bright jacket tied to a long stick and waved above the tree line.</string>
    <string name="signaling_item_high_ground_movement_step_1">Search and rescue teams are trained to look for movement and unnatural colors.</string>
    <string name="signaling_item_high_ground_movement_step_2">If you hear a helicopter or see rescuers, do not just stand still. Wave both arms above your head continuously.</string>
    <string name="signaling_item_high_ground_movement_step_3">Tie your brightest piece of clothing (orange, red, or bright blue) to a long stick and wave it rapidly like a flag. Movement catches the human eye much faster than a static shape.</string>
</resources>